Count your bullets.
Texas Rangers is a western, action, adventure film directed by Steve Miner.
Ten years after the Civil War has ended, the Governor of Texas asks Leander McNelly to
form a company of Rangers to help uphold the law along the Mexican border.
With a few veterans of the war, most of the recruits are young men who
have little or no experience with guns or policing crime.
Lincoln Rogers Dunnison, played by James Van Der Beek.
Caroline Dukes, played by Rachael Leigh Cook.
George Durham, played by Ashton Kutcher.
Leander McNelly, played by Dylan McDermott.
Randolph Douglas Scipio, played by Usher.
Richard Dukes, played by Tom Skerritt.
Texas Rangers is a 2001 American action Western film directed by Steve Miner and starring
James Van Der Beek, Ashton Kutcher, Alfred Molina, and Dylan McDermott.
It follows a group of Texas Rangers in the post-American Civil War era.
The film is very loosely based upon the book Taming the Nueces Strip by George Durham, who based it on his
own experiences serving in Captain Leander McNelly's Texas Ranger group as a young man.
The film was panned by critics and was a box office bomb.
The film explores themes of tiger, texas, texas ranger,
usa–mexico border, racial segregation.
The tone is emotional and intense.